<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Hugo tranquilpeak theme</title>
    <link>https://blog.shotwell.ca/categories/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Hugo tranquilpeak theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.shotwell.ca/categories/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Advice for non-traditional data scientists&#34;</title>
      <link>https://blog.shotwell.ca/post/learning-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.shotwell.ca/post/learning-data-science/</guid>
      <description>I have a pretty strange background for a data scientist. In my career I’ve sold electric razors, worked on credit derivatives during the 2008 financial crash, written market reports on orthopaedic biomaterials, and practiced law. I started programming in R during law school, partly as a way to learn more about data visualization and partly to help analyze youth criminal justice data. Over time I came to enjoy programming more than law and decided to make the switch to data work about three years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;R for Excel Users&#34;</title>
      <link>https://blog.shotwell.ca/post/r-for-excel-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.shotwell.ca/post/r-for-excel-users/</guid>
      <description>Like most people, I first learned to work with numbers through an Excel spreadsheet. After graduating with an undergraduate philosophy degree, I somehow convinced a medical device marketing firm to give me a job writing Excel reports on the orthopedic biomaterials market. When I first started, I remember not knowing how to anything, but after a few months I became fairly proficient with the tool, and was able to build all sorts of useful models.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
